rubiconproject.com 2010-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Rubicon Project

Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use any information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services.    
 **  
Only 22% of Internet Users** regularly review privacy policies for the sites they visit.  That is why this page may not look like other privacy policies you may have seen.  Unlike the average privacy policy which is approximately 2,500 words, the Rubicon Project offers this simple **300 word summary**.  

Like any summary, however, the Privacy Dashboard is not an exhaustive description of our privacy practices and should not be construed to define or limit the scope or extent of our Privacy Policy which is set forth in full below.

## PRIVACY DASHBOARD

#### Data We Collect

the Rubicon Project does not collect personally identifiable information (“PII”) except where users voluntarily provide such information via email or via registration for certain services or newsletters. We do collect non-PII such as your IP address, domain names, referring website addresses, and some online Web browsing activity.  (More Info)

#### How We Use Data

We use any PII data collected to contact you, and use any non-PII collected to enable our clients to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you.   (More Info)

#### Data Sharing

We do not rent, sell or disseminate PII to third parties for promotional purposes without your consent.  We only share data with trusted third parties who are under obligation to use the data in a responsible manner. (More Info)

#### You are in Control!

Within our Transparency and Control page, you can see the data we have stored about you, elect to discontinue further data collection by the Rubicon Project, or opt-out of targeted ads using this data.  You may also use the NAI’s consumer opt-out link below to opt-out of targeted ads from participating members.

#### Changes

We may change the Privacy Policy at any time by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Website and if such changes are material, a notice of the changes will also be posted along with the revised Privacy Policy.

#### Security

We use reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect your data.  (More Info)

#### Information & Questions

For a more detailed explanation of our privacy practices please read the full policy below. Any questions you may have should be directed to Marketing team at (310) 207-0272.

#### Certifications

Our Privacy Policy and practices have been certified by or are in compliance with TRUSTe and the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.  See Policy for details.

## PRIVACY POLICY

Last Updated: November 12, 2009

The Rubicon Project is a licensee of the TRUSTe Web Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build user’s trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Web site rubiconproject.com and any information we may collect through our customers’ Web sites.  Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

| 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Marketing at (310) 207-0272.  If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concern  
  
---|---  
  
To really understand any one company’s privacy practices, it helps to understand their business.  There likely are similarities between this policy and the policy on the website for your church, your school, your local coffee shop or your favorite online store but we all perform different services.  

the Rubicon Project offers premium website publishers a technology platform that gives them complete control and visibility over their advertising inventory, and matches every impression with the highest paying demand source. Almost all of the information we collect is from or through the web publishers and advertisers who utilize our service and not directly from consumers.

### Data We Collect

When you visit our Web site you may provide us with personally identifiable information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis. When you visit our customers’ Web sites, you may provide us with non-personally identifiable information collected on an aggregate basis.

#### Personally identifiable Information (“PII”)

Our customers are asked to provide the following:  Name, Company Name, Mailing Address, Email Address, Phone Number, Basic Site Information (URL, Channel, Impression Traffic), Username, Tax I.D. Number and Password.

In addition, if you choose to correspond with us through email or blog postings, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.

#### Non-Personally identifiable Information (“Non-PII”)

Similar to other commercial Web sites, we collect information about how customers’ Web sites are used and to determine user response to advertisements and promotions.  

Non-PII collected includes the following: IP address, domain, browser type and language, referring Web site addresses, date/time of visits, page view data, and search keywords.  Non-PII is collected using the following standard web technologies:

  * “Cookies” are data files, which often include an anonymous unique identifier, sent to your browser from a web site. Cookies can only be read by the party placing the cookie, they cannot erase or alter any of your data and they do not include personal data.  For more information about cookies visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 
  * “Log files” track actions occurring on Sites and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, click data and types of advertisements viewed. 
  * "Web beacons" are electronic files used to track your navigation of a website or collection of sites, the completion of transactions, submittal of applications and browsing behavior.

Collectively these technologies enable us to better understand and segment our customers’ audiences on an aggregate basis. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not store any personal information that you provided to us in your cookies.

### How We Use The Information

Broadly speaking, while we may collect and use personal information such as email address, name and phone number for purposes of administering and expanding our business activities, providing customer service and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers; our core business services rely on non-PII collected to match advertisers and website publishers. This benefits web users by enabling advertisers to deliver ad content that is relevant to interests or to respect a user’s preference to not receive certain advertisements.

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special opportunities we think you will find valuable. You may notify us at any time if you do not wish to receive these offers by emailing us at [care@rubiconproject.com](mailto:care@rubiconproject.com).

### Sharing Your Information

As indicated above, we do not collect PII except when provided voluntarily by visitors to our Web site.  We do not rent, sell or disseminate PII to third parties for promotional purposes without consent.   We will only share this voluntarily-provided PII

  * to enable third party service providers to assist or facilitate in the services we provide; 
  * to comply with applicable laws and regulations or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; 
  * to enforce an agreement or to protect our rights; with any parent, affiliated or successor entity;
  * in connection with any asset sale, transfer, divestiture or liquidation; 
  * in connection with strategic alliances, partnerships or other business arrangements to permit the offering of products or services we think may be of interest to you or where we have determined that the information will be used in a responsible manner by the third party; or
  * as permitted under any agreement with you. 

### Your Choices

On this site’s Transparency and Control page, you can see all the non-PII we have collected and which may be used for targeted advertising.  To discontinue our collection of non-PII click here and then select “Please discontinue all affinity profiling. Maybe I'll come back later and opt-in”.

To opt-out of behavioral advertising programs of members participating in the Network Advertising Initiatives opt-out program click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or use the consumer opt-out above.

You may request access to all your voluntarily-provided PII that we collected online and maintain in our database by emailing [globalsupport@rubiconproject.com](mailto:globalsupport@rubiconproject.com). To discontinue receiving updates or newsletters from us, or the sharing of any of your information with third parties (other than as may be necessary for compliance purposes or to protect our rights) contact [globalsupport@rubiconproject.com](mailto:globalsupport@rubiconproject.com).

### Security

We use appropriate measures to ensure the security of all Information, including the use of passwords, firewalls, encryption and remote servers, and routinely evaluate our practices to identify security threats or opportunities for the improvement of our services. No transmission of information is guaranteed to be completely secure. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise data security. You acknowledge and agree to assume this risk when communicating with us.

### Changes

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

### Third Party Websites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites or applications (including widgets) linked to or from our Web site nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Web site.  Please remember that your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including Web sites which have a link on our Web site, is subject to that Web site’s own rules and policies.

### Certifications

In addition to TRUSTe, our Privacy Policy and practices have been certified by or are in compliance with:

  * Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising
  * EU Safe Harbor

1925 S Bundy Drive, Los Angeles Ca. 90025 To contact the site please email us at [care@rubiconproject.com](mailto:care@rubiconproject.com)
